# Tony Olagbaiye

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tonyolag/ jobs@fron.io | 07944 843622

## PROFILE



Born: July 1996 Nationality: Black British

**Profile:** A Computer Science and Maths enthusiast with experience in a variety of programming languages, platforms and development environments, and a natural passion for developing and applying knowledge.

# SKILLS

## **PROGRAMMING**

Fluent

C • C++ • C# • Java • Haskell SQL • Python2 • CSS • Shell Purescript • Python3 • ATFX

Competent

Rust • Javascript • PHP • Go Scheme • Clojure • Assembly HTML5 • OCaml • Typescript

Familiar

Ruby • CLisp • F# Perl • Lua • Ada

#### **LANGUAGES**

Fluent

English (Native)

Competent

Japanese • Spanish

Familia

French • Italian • Mandarin • Finnish

#### **PLATFORMS**

Fluent

Linux (inc. RHEL, Debian) • FreeBSD NetBSD • POSIX • Azure

Competent

Windows • Android • Web

Familiar

OSX • Embedded • AWS

## BIOGRAPHY

I have had reasonable experience in the Tech Sector both as a student, in industry and in freelance. As a hobbyist, I am always up to date with the latest tech, conventions, and trends, and even outside quantifiable corporate experience I have years of casual experience with almost all forms of IT, from the theoretical, to the baremetal.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# DULWICH COLLEGE | CHAIRMAN OF THE PROGRAMMING SOCIETY

Sept 2013 - Jun 2014 | London

• Tasked with running and maintaining DC ProgSoc, including leading weekly sessions teaching aspects of programming for new and experienced students.

## UNIVERSITY OF YORK | FIRST AND SECOND YEAR

Sept 2014 - Jun 2016 | York

#### THALES UK LTD | SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

June 2016 - Jun 2017 | Manchester

 Took part in day to day running of software projects and meetings, including SCRUM meetings. Worked in Javascript/Angular JS and C++/Boost, using IBM Rhapsody and Rational Clearcase.

#### UNIVERSITY OF YORK | THIRD YEAR

Sept 2017 - Jun 2018 | York

#### MOSAIC FULFILMENT SOLUTIONS | GRADUATE DEVELOPER

Aug 2018 - Jun 2019 | Wetherby

- Took part in daily SCRUM meetings, infrastructure management and administration, full stack development and maintenance of a critical web app suite used internally and sold externally, liaising with clients and internal resources for support queries and specification, full end-to-end development of in-house data operations utilities, and most commonly SQL development and administration from the creation and maintenance of highly volatile databases containing tens of tables with millions of rows, to development of efficient and maintainable procedures and system agent jobs for data manipulation.
- Worked in Javascript/Typescript/Asp.Net-Core/Linq/SCSS, MS SQL Server 14/17, C#, using Visual Studio, VSTS/TFS, and SQL Server Management Studio.

#### ANSWER DIGITAL | .NET DEVELOPER

July 2019 - March 2020 | Leeds

- Functioning as a mid-tier developer. First project being an NHS team integration in Manchester, colocated 3 days a week. Working on a full stack web app for client internal use with a .Net backend, Aurelia/Typescript frontend, and a combination of SQL and MongoDB for storage (depending on security requirements). Second being a pioneer greenfield project for RPMI, replacing one side of a poor quality project completed by a previous service. The client in this case decided to colocate to us, and this used a .Net backend and JQuery/vanillaJS frontend due to requirements including use of Sitefinity as a CMS. The infrastructure was entirely Microsoft technologies, primarily Azure, and the site security (which was my primary concern) was almost entirely home grown.
- All projects function using AGILE methodologies as a top tier requirement, with daily scrum meetings, and/or whatever form of kanban is best applicable to the task. Lastly, regularly helped with the Answer Academy to train new recruits.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **DULWICH COLLEGE**

Graduated Aug 2014

A-Levels

A\*, A in Further Maths

2 extra unaccredited maths modules

B in Physics C in Chemistry

**GCSE** 

11 GCSEs

of which 10 A\*/A (inc. Maths, English)

## UNIVERSITY OF YORK

# COMPUTER SCIENCE WITH MATHEMATICS

[GG1K]

(With a year in industry)

First Year

Theory and Practice of Programming, Computer Architecture, Mathematics of Computer Science, Core

Algebra & Calculus

Second Year

Vision and Graphics, Principles of Programming Languages, Computation and Complexity, Artificial Intelligence, Intro to Number Theory, Group Theory,

Ring Theory, Linear Algebra

Third Year

Programming Correctness by Construction, Neural Computing and Applications, Information and Coding Theory, Dynamical Systems, Metric Spaces, Algebraic Number Theory, Cryptography, Topology, Galois

Theory

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

2016	Enlisted	Google Get Ahead Scheme
2014	1 <sup>st</sup> Round	UoY Raspberry Pi Challenge
2013	Participation	British Informatics Olympiad
2013	Silver Award	Senior Mathematics Challenge
2012	2 <sup>nd</sup> Round	Intermediate Mathematics Challenge

# REFERENCES

Edward Phillips

Mosaic Manager York House Wetherby Road York, YO26 7NH

01904 202 140

edward.phillips@mosaic-fs.co.uk

Emma Andrews

Answer Digital People Coordinator

Union Mills 9 Dewsbury Road Leeds, LS11 5DD

0113 201 0600

emma.andrews@answerdigital.co.uk

Typeset in LualAT<sub>F</sub>X